so for the VAW let's discuss the good
and the bad size of it among the good
things is that the compiler does the
hard work because the compiler is run
only once and then we run the program
many times the compiler can have plenty
of time to figure out a good schedule in
contrast in an out-of-order processor we
have very little time to come up with a
decent schedule because any time we
spend figuring out the schedule is the
time we are adding to the program
execution time the viola w processor
typically will have simpler hardware
than a comparable out of order processor
a viola W processor can be more energy
efficient than an out-of-order processor
because the harder had less to do per
executed instruction and the viola w
processors typically work really well on
loops and so-called regular code where
regular code is basically things like
sweeping through arrays multiplying
matrices and other things that the
compiler can easily figure out and then
schedule well around it the bad side of
vli w are that latencies of instructions
are not always the same the compiler has
to assume some sort of latency in order
to schedule code well but sometimes the
latencies cannot be determined exactly
so for example we can plan for a load to
have a cache hit latency but then when
it has a cache miss suddenly there is a
much longer latency than the compiler
planned for second many applications are
irregular almost every application that
does a lot of decision-making
like for example AI applications
applications that work on pointers or
pointer intensive structures and so on
are very hard for the compiler to figure
out and finally there is the code plot
issue we have already seen in our quiz
that the code for a viola W can be much
larger than the code for a normal out of
order processor because we are inserting
a lot of knobs to prevent things that
are dependent on each other from being
in the same large instruction